Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1918-88; Series I; 7.35; (18 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Houghton, Norris, 1958 Jan 6 (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Howell, Douglas M., 1980, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Hunterdon County Jury Commission, 1977, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Huppler, Dudley, 1950-64, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Hyslop, Paul, [1980] Jun 6 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - "I" general, 1969-79, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Inge, William, 1955, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Isherwood, Christopher, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Ivry, Benjamin, 1982 Jun 25 (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - "J" general, 1959-83, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Jackson, Frederick, 1939-66, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Janis, Sidney, 1972-78 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1977 Nov 15 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Johnson, Philip, 1960 Nov 11 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Johnson, Ruth, 1969-80 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - "K" general, 1947-87, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - Karp, Vickie, 1984, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 154a)
    - Katz, Leslie, 1973-80, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - Kauffer, E. McKnight, 1940-52 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - [Kauffman, Herbert H.], 1965 Sep 12 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Kinsey, Clara, 1954 Dec 16 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1942, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Knollys, Eardley, 1936, 1982, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Kuh, Frederick, 1965-82, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - "L" general, 1955-88, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 163-164)
    - Lawson, Kate Drain, 1963 Jul 10 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Leavitt, David, 1950-78, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Lee, Douglas, 1976 Sep 16 (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - [Leffert, Henry?], 1955 Aug 27 (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Lesemann, Maurice, 1918, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Lewis, David, 1980-85, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 170)
      includes card from MW
    - [Lightheart, Ella?], 1919, 1940, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - Lightheart, Ida, 1918 Dec 6 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - [Lightheart?], Norm, 1918-19 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1950 Dec 22 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Lippold, Richard, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Littlefield, Lester, 1956-69 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Littlefield, William, 1949-66 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Loos, Anita, 1972 Dec 30 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Lord, James, 1967, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Lowery, Bruce, 1961 Oct 1 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Ludwig, Richard, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Lynes, Adelaide, 1933 Apr 29
    - Lynes, George Platt, 1935-55, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Lynes, Russell; Lynes, Mildred, 1936-77, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 183)
      to MW & GPL; includes letter from MW
    - "M" general, 1954-88, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 184-186)
    - McDermott, Eugene, Mrs. [Margaret], 1973-85, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - McIlhenny, Henry, 1966 Sep 1 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - MacIver, Loren; Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1962-70 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Macleish, Archibald, 1937, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Magritte, René, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 191)
      [translation of letter only]
    - [Mander?], Jane
    - Mann, Thomas, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 192)
      includes letter from MW and from TM to Prof. Curtius
    - Mardersteig, Hans (Giovanni), 1936, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 193)
      [one card also signed by Helen and Kurt Wolff]
    - Matisse, Pierre, 1938-75 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Maxwell, William; Maxwell, Emmy, 1964, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Mayor, A. Hyatt, 1944, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - [Meloni?], R. L., 1919 (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - Messières, René de, from MW, 1951 Feb 20
    - Miller, Christian William, Jr., 1948-75, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 199-200)
    - MW to Miller, Christian William, Jr., 1946-70, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 201-204)
    - Mitford, Nancy, 1950 Sep 8 (Box 7, Folder 205)
      to MW
    - Mitzlaff, Maximilian H., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Moltke, Mab, 1960-78 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - Mondrian, Piet, 1942 Mar 5 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - [Montgomery, George?], 1951, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - Moore, Henry, 1947, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 210)
      to MW; includes letter from MW
    - Moore, John Warner; Moore, Constance, 1947-72, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1930-67, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 212-216)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1922-65, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 217-226)
      photocopies of letters; mostly to MW, includes several to GW
    - MW to Moore, Marianne, 1937-62, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - Moore, Mary Warner, 1938-47 (Box 9, Folder 228)
    - Morot-Sir, Edouard, 1966 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Mortimer, Raymond, 1949-77, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 230-231)
      See Clippings - Kinsey, Alfred for items included with letter of 1953 Aug 25
    - "N" general, 1970-88, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Namara, Marguerite, 1965-72, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - National Gallery of Art, 1978 Feb 3 (Box 9, Folder 234)
    - Nesbitt, J. R., 1918 Sep 19 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - Newhall, Beaumont, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - New Jersey, Department of Education, 1971 Nov 4 (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - Ney, Elly, 1922, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Nin-Culmel, Joaquin, 1977, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - [Nolan, Dorothee?], 1938 Jan 27 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - "O" general, 1940-84, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Ocampo, Victoria, 1962-66, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - Olds, Irving S., 1955 Mar 2
    - Oliver, Maria Rosa, 1969 Apr 26 (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - Otero, Alejandro, 1960-82 (Box 9, Folder 244)
    - Otton, William, 1983-85 (Box 9, Folder 245)
    - "P" general, 1950-88, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 246)
    - P. L. N. Y., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 246a)
      Includes letter from Tambimuttu and letters from MW
    - Page, Chester, 1964 Sep (Box 9, Folder 246b)
      Includes letter from MW
    - Parker, Robert Andrew, 1956 Oct 1 (Box 9, Folder 247)
    - Parkinson, Elizabeth B., 1962-81, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 248)
    - Perlin, Bernard, 1952-84, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 249)
    - Pevsner, Antoine, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 250)
    - Phelps, Robert, 1964-70, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1938 Oct (Box 9, Folder 252)
      [from Belle da Costa Greene]
    - Plomer, William, 1961 Aug 15 (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - Pohorilenko, Anatole, 1969-86, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 254-256)
    - Pomeroy, Ralph, 1951-87, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 257-259)
    - Pope-Hennessey, James, 1967 Jun 26 (Box 10, Folder 260)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1962-65, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 261)
    - Porter, Paul, 1979 Sep (Box 10, Folder 262)
    - Portinari, Candido; Portinari, Maria, 1941, 1964, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - Preston, Stuart, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 264)
    - Pryce-Jones, Alan, 1967, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 265)
      includes letter to Raymond [Mortimer?] from APJ
    - Pulitzer, Joseph, Jr., 1964 Oct 21 (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - Queens Museum, 1976 Aug 19 (Box 10, Folder 267)
    - "R" general, 1960-88, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 268)
    - Rain, Charles, 1944, 1959, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 269)
    - Ransom, Will, 1950 May 14 (Box 10, Folder 269a)
    - Ray, Satyajit, 1976 Jun 28 (Box 10, Folder 270)
    - Reichenbach, François, 1950 Aug 21 (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - Richards, Mona, 1968, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - Rindge (Claflin), Agnes, 1937, 1955, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 273)
      to MW & GPL
    - Roberts, Elizabeth Maddox, 1930, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 274)
      [photocopies only]
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette, 1948-87, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 275)
    - Rockefeller, David, 1965-88 (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - Rockefeller, Happy, 1967, 1969, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - Rockefeller, John D., III, 1956-74 (Box 11, Folder 278)
    - Rockefeller, Mary ("Tod"), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 279)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1937-77, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 280-281)
    - Rodman, Selden, 1970 Mar 4 (Box 11, Folder 282)
    - Rogers, Bruce, 1951 Jan 25 (Box 11, Folder 283)
    - Roos, S. H. de, 1934 Feb 20
    - Rosco, Jerry, 1981 Feb 24 (Box 11, Folder 284)
    - Rose, Francis, 1934 Feb 19
    - Rothschild, Pauline de, 1945-73, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 285)
    - Rothschild, Philippe de, 1967-87, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 286)
    - Rouault, [Isabelle?], 1953 Mar 16 (Box 11, Folder 287)
    - Roy, Pierre, 1946-47 (Box 11, Folder 288)
    - Russell, John, 1969 Dec 27 (Box 11, Folder 289)
    - Rutgers University, 1961, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 290)
    - Ryan, Nin, 1960, 1964, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 291)
    - "S" general, 1924-88, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 292-294)
    - Salles, Georges, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 295)
    - Sasson, Victor, 1933, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 296)
    - Schmerler, David, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 297)
    - Schoeborn, Florene, 1960-68, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 298)
    - Shawe-Taylor, Desmond, 1958-82, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 299)
    - Sheean, Dinah, 1964, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 300)
    - Sihare, Laxmi, 1967-79, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 301)
      includes envelope of clippings from MW
    - Simmonds, Harvey, 1967-77, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 302)
    - Simmons, John; Simmons, Ellie, 1979-84 (Box 11, Folder 303)
    - Simmons, Liz, 1970, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 304)
    - Sitwell, Osbert, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 305)
    - Smith, G. E. Kidder, 1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 306)
    - Snow, Carmel, 1947 Oct 6 (Box 11, Folder 307)
    - Soby, James Thrall, 1949-72 (Box 12, Folder 308)
    - Soutter, Jérome, 1949, 1951, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 309)
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 12, Folder 310)
    - Sperison, Albert, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 311)
    - Stait, Walter, 1975, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 312)
    - Standard, Paul, 1936-70 (Box 12, Folder 313)
    - Steinberg, Saul, 1951 Apr 16 (Box 12, Folder 314)
    - Stern, Jimmy, 1983 Jan 17 (Box 12, Folder 315)
      includes copy of letter to JS from "Gene", 1938 Mar 17
    - Stern, Joanne, 1984-85, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 316)
    - Strand, Paul, 1952, 1963, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 317)
    - Strauss, Beth, 1962-81, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - Strychalski, Joshua, 1977-87 (Box 12, Folder 319)
    - Sutherland, Graham, 1950 Sep 21 (Box 12, Folder 320)
    - Szarkowski, John, 1975 Feb 18 (Box 12, Folder 321)
    - Szladits, Lola, 1975, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 322)
    - Szold-Fritz, Bernardine, 1959-81, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 323-324)
    - "T" general, 1948-83, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 325)
    - Tanguy, Kay, 1962 Dec 14 (Box 12, Folder 326)
    - Tawney, Lenore, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 327)
      to Barbara Wescott & MW
    - Thayer, Jeanne; Thayer, Walter, 1977, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 328)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1980-81 (Box 12, Folder 329)
    - Thurber, James, 1952 Feb 8 (Box 12, Folder 330)
    - Tooker, George, 1961, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 331)
    - Tyng, Lila, 1978, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 332)
    - "U" general, 1950-71, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 333)
    - University of Maryland, 1971-78 (Box 12, Folder 334)
    - University of Texas, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 335)
    - Ursus Books, 1981, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 336)
    - "V" general, 1968-88 (Box 12, Folder 337)
    - Van Arsdale, William K., 1919-88 (Box 12, Folder 338)
    - Van Krimpen, Jan, 1933 Apr 10 (Box 12, Folder 339)
    - [Victors?], E., 1933 Sep 29
    - Vidal, Yves, 1950, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 340)
    - Villon, Jacques, 1961 Feb 18 (Box 12, Folder 341)
    - Vreeland, Diana, 1964-68 (Box 12, Folder 342)
    - "W" general, 1947-87, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 343-344)
    - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1963 (Box 13, Folder 345)
      See also: Series III, Personal Papers, Box 121, folder 1436
    - W., Faith, 1921, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 346)
    - Wadsworth, Alice E., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 347)
    - Waldman, Bernard, 1974-80 (Box 13, Folder 348)
    - Walker, Herschel Carey, 1950-67, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 349)
    - Wallace, Benj. B., 1919 May 11 (Box 13, Folder 350)
    - Watson, Hildegarde, 1962, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 351)
    - Watson, Steven, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 352)
    - Watts, Schuyler, 1960-75, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 353)
    - Waugh, Alec, 1969 Apr 18 (Box 13, Folder 354)
    - Wescott, Barbara, n.d.
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1934, n.d.
    - White, Herbert B., 1918 Nov 16 (Box 13, Folder 355)
    - Whitney, Betsey, 1978, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 356)
    - Whitney, John Hay, 1960, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 357)
    - Wiemeler, Ignatz, 1951-52 (Box 13, Folder 358)
      includes death notice
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1958, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 359)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1922-23 (Box 13, Folder 360)
      [notebook of photocopies]
    - Willis, Patricia, 1979-87 (Box 13, Folder 361)
    - Wilson, Robert, 1986, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 362)
    - Wimmer, Kurt, 1936, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 363)
      to GW & MW
    - Wind, Edgar, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 364)
    - Winthrop, Emmeline, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 365)
    - Wojtasik, Ted, 1980-85 (Box 13, Folder 366)
      includes letter from TW to "Mary"
    - Wolff, Kurt, 1947 Nov 21 (Box 13, Folder 367)
    - World House Galleries, 1960-61 (Box 13, Folder 368)
    - Wrightsman, Jayne, 1965-72 n.d. (Box 13, Folder 369)
    - "Y-Z" general, 1957, 1988, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 370)
    - Zaoussailoff, Alexandra ["Choura"], 1957-72 (Box 13, Folder 371)
    - Zapf, Hermann, 1959-65 (Box 13, Folder 372)
    - Zayas, Marius de, 1948 May 15 (Box 13, Folder 373)
    - Zeisler, Richard, 1977 Aug 24 (Box 13, Folder 374)
    - Unidentified
      - MW: drafts to multiple persons, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 375)
      - "Min", 1980, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 376)
      - World War I-era friends, ca. 1919-20 (Box 14, Folder 377)
        includes: Meredith, Guess, Mac, Marion, Maurice, Steve, Art, Norman, [Noth?], and Buff
      - Unidentified to MW, 1920-87, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 378-381)
      - Unidentified from MW, 1961-87, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 382)
    - Christmas cards to GW & MW, 1940-74 (Box 15, Folder 383-398)
    - Christmas cards to GW & MW, 1975-87 (Box 16, Folder 399-411)
    - Christmas cards to GW & MW, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 412-418)
    - Blank cards from MW, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 419)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Anderson, Rose Marie to Clark, Deborah Wescott (Box 18, Folder 420)
    - "Bill" to "Mom and Dad", 1969 Feb 7 (Box 18, Folder 421)
    - Bunnell, Peter to McAlpin, David, 1983 Apr 4 (Box 18, Folder 422)
    - Campbell, Sandy to Wescott, Barbara, 1957 Mar 5 (Box 18, Folder 423)
    - Clark Tours to Wescott, Barbara, 1948 Feb 10 (Box 18, Folder 424)
    - Cottenet, R. L. to Nolan, Dorothy, 1944 Feb 20 (Box 18, Folder 425)
    - Etcheber, D. to "Madame", 1946 Nov 9 (Box 18, Folder 426)
    - Flanner, Janet to Duchamp, Marcel, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 427)
    - Grolier Club (Arthur A. Houghton, Jr.) to Moore, Marianne, 1956 Dec 13 (Box 18, Folder 428)
    - "J. P." to de la Grange, Henri Louis, 1951 Sept (Box 18, Folder 429)
    - Lee, Freddie to Dorothee Nolan, 1930 Nov 17
    - Lynes, George Platt to Miller, Christian William, Jr., 1944-51 (Box 18, Folder 430)
      includes letters from Jonathan Tichenor to CWM
    - Mann, Alfred to Allison, James B., 1963 Feb 26 (Box 18, Folder 431)
    - "Mary" to "Doris", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 432)
    - Metzdorf, Robert F. to Pierpont Morgan Library, 1969 Feb 21 (Box 18, Folder 433)
    - Moore, D. Langley, Mrs. to Mr. Sackville-West, 1961 Aug 5 (Box 18, Folder 434)
    - Moore, Marianne to Bryan, Julien, 1957 Aug 23 (Box 18, Folder 435)
      [photocopy]
    - Moore, Marianne to Lynes, George Platt, 1938-55 (Box 18, Folder 436)
    - Moore, Marianne to Waldman, Bernard, 1963 Jan 5 (Box 18, Folder 437)
    - Moore, Marianne to Wescott, Barbara, 1960 Jul 26 (Box 18, Folder 438)
    - Mortimer, Raymond to Fuller, Richard, 1971 Jan 18 (Box 18, Folder 439)
    - Mortimer, Raymond to Wescott, Barbara, 1973 Nov 1 (Box 18, Folder 440)
    - "Nels" to "Joi", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 441)
    - Perlin, Bernard to Miller, Christian William, 1952 Mar 30 (Box 18, Folder 442)
    - Pomeroy, Ralph to Miller, Christian William, 1959 Apr 20 (Box 18, Folder 443)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne to Lynes, Russell and Mildred, 1941-58 (Box 18, Folder 444)
      [copies]
    - [Pryce-Jones?], Alan to [Mortimer], Raymond, 1973 Sep 27 (Box 18, Folder 445)
    - [West?], Rebecca to Unidentified, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 446)
    - Rewald, John to Pryce-Jones, Alan [Times Literary Supplement], 1957 Apr 10 (Box 18, Folder 447)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A. to Gardner Cowles, 1960 Jun 29
    - Sotheby Parke Bernet, Inc. to Wescott, Lloyd, 1977 Jun 8 (Box 18, Folder 448)
    - Wescott, Barbara to MOMA, 1964 Oct 8 (Box 18, Folder 449)
    - Wescott, Lloyd to Friends of the Hunterdon Medical Center, 1976 Dec 10 (Box 18, Folder 450)
    - Wilder, Isabel to Hagen, Beulah, 1962 Apr (Box 18, Folder 451)
      includes response letter and notes by GW
    - Unidentified to "Dave", 1983 Mar 12 (Box 18, Folder 452)
    - Unidentified to Pomeroy, Ralph, 1962 May 7 (Box 18, Folder 453)
    - Unidentified to Wescott, Barbara, 1933 Sep 30 (Box 18, Folder 454)
    - Unidentified to Wescott, Lloyd, 1935 Mar 2 (Box 18, Folder 455)
- Writings, 1921-88, n.d.; Series II; 3.15; (8 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, consists of four subseries, all of which are arranged alphabetically by title or author.
  - GENERAL WRITINGS
    - Advertisement for publication: "The Immobile Wind" by Yvor Winters printed card, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 456)
    - Advertisement for publication: "The Living Frieze" by Mark Turbyfill, printed card, [1921] (Box 19, Folder 457)
    - AIGA citation to Leonard Baskin, printed version, 1965 Apr 28 (Box 19, Folder 458)
      with background information
    - Article: "A great collector of books recently showed me the treasures in his magnificent library." typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 459)
    - Central Manufacturing District Magazine: articles, printed versions, 1920-26 (Box 19, Folder 460-461)
    - Coal and Iron National Bank: advertisment drafts, typescript and carbon, ca. 1923-24 (Box 19, Folder 462)
    - Coal and Iron National Bank: advertising copy for Edgar C. Ruwe Co, Inc., typescript (Box 19, Folder 463)
    - Coal and Iron National Bank: Employee Service Code, draft, typescript carbon (Box 19, Folder 464)
    - Coal and Iron National Bank: pamphlets, 1923-24 (Box 19, Folder 465)
    - Coal and Iron National Bank: printed advertisments, ca. 1923-24 (Box 19, Folder 466)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", correspondence, 1974-82 (Box 19, Folder 467)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", proposed working outline (Box 19, Folder 468)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", notebook with draft pages, 1982-83 (Box 19, Folder 469)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", Foreword by MW, notes and draft pages, ca. 1982-83 (Box 19, Folder 470)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", Foreword by MW, notes and drafts, holograph, typescript, photocopy and computer printout, corrected, ca. 1982-83 (Box 19, Folder 471)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", Foreword by MW, printed version, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 472)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", catalog entry for Bonnard's "Intérieur", draft, typescript, corrected (Box 19, Folder 473)
    - "The David and Peggy Rockefeller Collection", list of artworks, annotated (Box 19, Folder 474)
    - "Escape to Mexico", outline, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 475)
    - "I Remember MOMA", notes, ca. 1979 (Box 19, Folder 476)
    - "I Remember MOMA", notebook with draft pages, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 477-479)
    - "I Remember MOMA", draft pages, typescript, carbon and photocopy, corrected, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 480)
    - "I Remember MOMA", proof page, corrected, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 481)
    - "I Remember MOMA", galley proof, corrected, with photocopy, ca. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 482)
    - "I Remember MOMA", printed version, Artnews, 1979 Oct (Box 20, Folder 483)
    - "In Ceylon with Waugh", notebook with draft pages and clippings, ca. 1957-76 (Box 21, Folder 484)
      [some sections written by GW]
    - "In Praise of Indian Textiles", printed version, American Women's Club of New Delhi Fashion Festival program, 1956 Oct 20 (Box 21, Folder 485)
    - "Junior Book Clinic Honor", printed version, Publisher's Weekly, 1939 Jun 3 (Box 21, Folder 486)
    - "Meeting Picasso", printed version, University Review, 1937 Spring (Box 21, Folder 487)
    - "Meeting Picasso", offprint from University Review, 1937 Spring (Box 21, Folder 488)
    - "Meeting Picasso", printed version, A Just God, 1983 Jun (Box 21, Folder 489)
    - "The Museum as Publisher", printed version, Art in America, 1946 Oct (Box 21, Folder 490)
    - Notebook containing draft of historical narrative re: France during the reign of Charles the Ninth, ca. 1930 (Box 21, Folder 490a)
      Also includes: "Prologue to Atala" by George Platt Lynes, typescript, corrected, 1930 Apr
    - Obituary of Marianne Moore for the Yale Alumni Magazine, draft, typescript and photocopy, 1972 Feb 26 (Box 21, Folder 491)
    - Presentation slip for "Like a Lover" by Glenway Wescott, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 491a)
    - "Recommendation for Richard Kemble for Rome Fellowship Prize", draft, typescript (Box 21, Folder 492)
    - "Report to the Advisory Committee on Graduate Studies, Rutgers University", draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1964 Mar 31 (Box 21, Folder 493)
    - Review of The Passionate Sightseer by Bernard Berenson, draft, typescript carbon, 1960 May 27 (Box 21, Folder 494)
    - Review of The Passionate Sightseer by Bernard Berenson, printed version, New York Herald Tribune Book Review, 1960 Jun 12 (Box 21, Folder 495)
    - "The Search for Summer", draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 496)
    - Unititled story drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, ca. 1923-24 (Box 21, Folder 497)
    - Untitled draft pages (some on art), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 498-499)
  - LECTURES & SPEECHES
    - "AIGA Gold Medal to Ben Shahn", notecards, 1958 Nov 13 (Box 21, Folder 500)
    - "The Artist Temperament as a Factor in Modern Art", invitation, 1963 Feb (Box 21, Folder 501)
    - "Enjoyment of Art", background clippings, ca. 1948-52 (Box 21, Folder 502)
      [also titled "How to Enjoy Art"]
    - "Enjoyment of Art", background printed items, ca. 1929-54 (Box 22, Folder 503)
    - "Enjoyment of Art", Life round table at MOMA, prospectus, member list, and clippings, 1948 Jul (Box 22, Folder 504)
    - "Enjoyment of Art", notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 505)
    - "Enjoyment of Art", notecards, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 506)
    - "Enjoyment of Art", draft pages, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 507)
    - Introduction of W. H. Auden at the Grolier Club, notecards, 1946 Oct 24 (Box 22, Folder 508)
    - Introduction of Pierre Blanchard, notecards, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 509)
    - Introduction of Hyatt Mayor at the Grolier Club, notecards, 1944 Nov 16 (Box 22, Folder 510)
    - "Introduction of Marianne Moore Upon her Adressing the Grolier Club", drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, [1948] (Box 22, Folder 511)
      with program
    - Introduction for José Clemente Orozco, notecards, ca. 1945 (Box 22, Folder 512)
    - Introduction for Edith Sitwell (portraying Lady MacBeth), notecards, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 513)
    - Introduction for Dr. Edgar Wind's "The Heritage of Baudelaire", draft, typescript, corrected (Box 22, Folder 514)
    - Lacouriere lecture: New York Public Library / AIGA, notecards, 1949 Oct 18 (Box 22, Folder 515)
    - "Launching the 50 Prints", printed version, News-letter of the American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1938 Jun (Box 22, Folder 516)
    - "Meeting the Artists", contract, 1977 Sep 16 (Box 22, Folder 517)
    - "Moral Value of Art", notecards, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 518)
    - "On Art: What it is and What it has Meant to Me", draft pages (Box 22, Folder 519)
    - Phenomenal Popularity of Modern Art, notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 520)
    - Presentation of AIGA medal to Will Sandberg, draft, typescript, corrected, 1962 Oct 24 (Box 22, Folder 521)